<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Wallup</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">MainActivity</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="section_format">Hello World from section: %1$d</string>

    <string name="long_text">erena Williams’s legacy as the most dominant player in tennis speaks for itself. But this week, retired player John McEnroe — who himself is a legendary tennis player and member of the International Tennis Hall of Fame — decided to put his own strange stamp on it.

In an interview with NPR that quickly drew backlash, McEnroe belittled, albeit perhaps inadvertently, Williams’s legacy. He was asked about the greatest tennis players of the sport, and said that while Williams has been dominating women’s tennis since 1999, “if she played the men\'s circuit she\'d be like 700 in the world.”

“That doesn’t mean I don’t think Serena is an incredible player,” McEnroe continued. “I do, but the reality of what would happen would be I think something that perhaps it’d be a little higher, perhaps it’d be a little lower. And on a given day, Serena could beat some players.”

While McEnroe isn’t entirely wrong — Williams has said similar things in the past, and in 1998 she played an exhibition match and lost to the 203rd-ranked male player — his observation, especially the 700 number he seems to have pulled out of nowhere, seems unnecessary. Williams’s litany of accomplishments (which include 23 grand slam championship wins and counting, Olympic gold medals, $84 million in prize money won, and a grand slam tournament win while pregnant) doesn’t need wins over male tennis players to justify its greatness.

Since he first made the comment, McEnroe has been the subject of plenty of outrage for diminishing Williams’s career in a flippant way. And he’s responded by doubling down on his assertions, even throwing out the idea of combining the men’s and women’s tours to prove who is really the best.

At a glance, his stubborn behavior and controversy courting may seem brash and even strange for a man who in the past has gushed about how dominant and transcendent of an athlete Williams is. But there’s also another factor at play here: McEnroe’s got a book to sell.

The controversy started when McEnroe got himself into trouble with a clumsy NPR interview
Right now the tennis season is in a bit of a lull as players gear up for the next grand slam — the four major tournaments (the Australian Open, French Open, Wimbledon, and US Open) — of the sport’s season. The Australian Open concluded earlier this year, the French Open ended earlier this month, and Wimbledon officially starts on July 3.

Even though McEnroe has been retired for years, grand slam tournaments are still an opportunity for him to take home a paycheck — he’s worked as a commentator for CBS, NBC, USA, and ESPN to analyze players’ strategies, temperaments, and tendencies and offer live commentary on how a match is unfolding.

His interview with NPR this week was a rare instance when people heard McEnroe’s thoughts on tennis outside the context of a televised match. In that interview, which is part of McEnroe’s promotional book tour for his new memoir, NPR’s Lulu Garcia-Navarro asked him a series of questions about the best players in the history of the sport, eventually bringing up Serena Williams.

What’s fascinating about this interaction is that Garcia-Navarro does a good job of getting McEnroe to talk himself into a bit of trouble. It’s not like he makes a totally unprompted and organic observation about Williams being ranked 700th; he’s pushed and prodded into it a bit. Here’s the full exchange (emphasis mine):</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
</resources>
